I am going to talk about campuses now there a handy thing to help you keep on track.
There is a number of different styles of campuses and you can really get confused looking at them.
But you really need to look at what kind of navigating your going to do.
If your going to use a map my preference is some form of a base plate campus.
Base plate campus has a little plate and you can use that plate to line up between a couple objects on the map.
There are also ones with a sighting mirror that allows you to hold it look through it like a little gun sight at an object in the distance and look at the campus at the same time.
It helps you to take a bearing off of something.
The downside of that for a backpacker it becomes heavier and I know it is maybe an half an ounce but backpackers think in terms of that.
This right here is a lensatic campus.
More of a military style nice thing about the numbers for the bearing are actually on the needle.
So as you turn it it turns.
Base plate campuses has a little dial.
So you have to play with it to see which style is to your preference.
If you want something a little simpler you can go to ones more like this a little fish eye campus that you can just kind of pin to your pack.
You just need to know which way is north, south, east, west.
This particular one is a key chain style or I have used them as zipper pulls.
It has a campus but it also has a thermometer which is kind of nice when you?re out on the trail to know what the temperature like.
If you have any questions about campuses give your local outfitter a holler.